hi everybody welcome back to the channel
it's another scorcher here in the uk
we're just not equipped for
warm temperatures our houses are
designed to keep the heat in and one of
the best ways to cool down is ice cream
i mean that's what i tell myself anyway
this is not a flavor i would normally
try make my wife love strawberry ice
cream so we thought we'd grab this from
the store as it was on offer
and we're gonna try and recreate it so
i've actually never had harker dolls of
strawberry before
so
let's open it up and see what it's like
[Music]
you probably can't see that's uh
the light is made to look white but it's
a very subtle pink color
[Music]
really light strawberry smell
it's hard as a rock
the haagen-dazs do say that you should
take it out the freezer for 95 days
before you serve it so just keep that in
mind
nice strawberry flavor
chunk of strawberry there icy
strawberries are 95 water
and unless you soak them in you know
glycerin or alcohol
they'll always be like
so it's actually surprisingly nice i'm
not really a fruit ice cream fan i like
chocolate ice cream
i think that's uh
let's give this one a bash but
let's see how close we can get to
recreating this but in vegan form why
because we're clearing the cupboards for
one reason or another now i've got lots
of vegan ingredients i want to use so
stick around for vegan
haagen-dazs
strawberry ice cream
so to start our vegan version of
haagen-dazs strawberries and cream
you're gonna take your strawberries and
you're gonna chop them up de-stalk and
then put them in your pan add to that
your sugar
this sugar will help to bring the
moisture out or the water out the
strawberries but we're also going to add
a little bit of lemon juice the acidity
will help to stabilize the solution and
it also stops the strawberries just
destroying
the structure completely then you're
going to heat that gently on the hob
until it just starts to bubble and you
start to get something ache into a jam
or conserve
texture if you live in england
once you've got it like that you can
take it off the heat and then put it in
the container and let it cool down
so once your strawberry mixture has
cooled you're going to take some of that
and put it in a little pot because what
we're going to do is pop it in our
little blender here and then just get it
completely macerated really fine you're
going to start with that in your pan to
that we're going to add our vegan
condensed milk
and then gently heat that up so it's
really nicely combined because that
vegan condensed milk is really quite a
stiff mixture
as it heats up we're then going to add
in our vegan cream or plant based cream
this is elm lee plant based cream i love
this stuff it's great we're going to add
two tubs of this they're 250 ml tubs and
then we're going to add in some more of
our strawberry
sauce and pieces as you can see there's
plenty of strawberry pieces in this base
we don't need to heat this up to
anything specific we're just trying to
keep it all nicely warmed and combined
once it's ready you can take it off the
hob and put it in a container
store that in the fridge for three to
four hours until completely chilled down
so once your base is completely churned
you're going to take it out the fridge
and just to boost that color we're going
to put in another 70 grams worth of your
strawberry mix and again this is
pretty much all of the strawberry mix
here going into the ice cream base give
it a nice stir and then pop it in your
machine
let it turn to the consistency you want
and then put it in a tub in the freezer
it goes for as long as you can wait
before eating it
[Music]
and here we are
we've got our
vegan
strawberry ice cream hopefully it's the
same i mean
wise i've got feeder nails might be a
little bit pinker
taste wise let's see i mean i love that
elm lee plant-based cream it's really
really good stuff it is by far the best
cream substitute that i've ever tried
there's a few out there but it is
excellent so let's get some of these
scooped up i'm going to put them on a
plate and see what they're like
[Music]
here we go both scooped about the same
and maybe ours was just a little bit
softer
i i obviously was in control of the
sugar i know
vegan recipes that use kind of off the
shelf
ingredients such as the vegan condensed
milk and the cream etc they can go a bit
harder so ideally if you're using those
you might want to just up the sugar
a few percent just to make it a little
bit easier on you or if you're happy to
wait
like you would do with the haagen-dazs
then don't leave it take it out of the
freezer put it in the fridge for 10-15
minutes before you want to serve it or
scoop it or eat it from the tub totally
up to you anyway
initial differences haagen-dazs is a
much lighter color than ours there's no
artificial coloring as you could see in
our tools it's all just natural
strawberry
let's see
how they taste when
compared
again haagen-dazs has a really nice
flavor it's kind of gentle
it's not
super strong strawberry flavor texture
is really good you'd expect that from
haagen-dazs anyway
little icy bits of strawberry in there
again like i said before they're 95
water so that's to be expected let's
dive into our vegan version and see how
we did
blimey
that's really good
it's a it's a stronger strawberry flavor
the texture is perfect there's no ice
apart from the little bits of strawberry
in there
again i don't even to repeat that again
but you've actually got
a better ice cream in vegan form than
the off-the-shelf luxury brand
haagen-dazs and you can do this at home
just by buying ingredients from your
supermarket
this is really good and i'm not a fruit
ice cream fan so
overall this is a 100 win and if you're
vegan then bloody well good on you
because you're in for a treat if you
make this so while the sun shines get
out there get the strawberries keep
making and let us know how it turns out
thanks for watching don't forget to like
and subscribe and we'll see you next
week
[Music]